# KEVIN S. CHOI

Cell: 408-621-5580 Email: <u>kevin@kchoi.co</u> Personal Site: <u>kchoi.co</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

Well-rounded DevOps & Site Reliability Engineer with 10+ years of experience in the TechOps industry. Specializing in infrastructure build outs, compute & network configurations, project management, and executive level documentation. Looking to expand my skills in site reliability, automation, and scalability.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

UCBerkeley Coding Bootcamp **2019**AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner: **W6Y2NVJCBEV11JK3**Splunk Fundamentals
Cisco Meraki Networking Associate
Palo Alto Networks Accredited Expert
Datto Certified Practitioner. Tech Cert

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Cloud Services: GCP, AWS, Heroku, CenturyLink, Softlayer Microservices: Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher, GKE Observability: New Relic, Grafana, Prometheus, DataDog, Splunk, CheckMK, Solarwinds, Zabbix, Nagios

CICD Tools: Jenkins, GitLabs

Config Management: Ansible, Terraform, helm, helmfile

Operating Systems: Linux, macOS, Windows

### **EDUCATION**

**B.A. Economics** - San Jose State University

#### **COURSE ACHIEVEMENTS**

Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services Google Cloud Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation

**Full-Stack:** Python, Bash, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL **Networking Stack:** Cloudflare, F5, Nginx, Cisco, Meraki, Fortigate, Palo Alto Networks, SonicaWALL

**Applications & Platforms:** VMWare, Hyper-V, TrueNAS, Cisco ISE, Qualys, ADAudit+, SeeBurger, Jscape, Control-M, Rundeck, Airflow, JFrog, Jboss, Memcached, Zookeeper

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### DevOps Engineer

**Prosper Marketplace**, Dec 2020 - Present

- Ensure Prosper site reliability and availability is at the forefront of every task or incident; including efficient scaling of Prospers CICD process.
- Influence Developers on best practices and the most efficient way to get the most out of our Jenkins CICD pipeline.
- Assist Developers on migrating Spring Boot v1.0 to Spring Boot v2.0 and implementing prometheus metrics through kubernetes service monitor to be ingested into Prometheus and Thanos instances.
- Migrate multiple kubernetes clusters that host 3,000+ Prosper microservices to newly improved Rancher clusters on-prem and on GKE.
- Update Prosper DevOps CLI tool using Python 3, CLI tool called P3, that manages all deployments and CICD functions using helm validations.
- Implemented helmfile to the DevOps team to fully automate new environment deployments of Ingress Nginx, Grafana+Prometheus, F5 BIG-IP Controller, and Hashicorp vault.
- Automate manual tasks using Jenkins, Rundeck, and Airflow to reduce human error and minimize tedious human involvement.

### Systems Engineer

**Prosper Marketplace,** Sept 2019 - Dec 2020

- Monitored, implemented, automated, and maintained critical production operation infrastructure, including upgrades, patch management, and troubleshooting.
- Developed custom scripts that are easily read and uploaded onto the System Engineering tools repository, such as
  archival scripts and parsing large inventory file python scripts, followed by documentations on use cases and edge
  cases.
- Identified TechOps business challenges for example shortage in storage space for Splunk Indexers and develop actionable solutions such as scaling out the Splunk infrastructure using automation process with Ansible, focussing on security and business continuity.
- Project managed company Linux environment patching and kernel upgrades, implementing best practices on updating repositories, coordinating with DevOps and other affected teams, and creating documentation and Jira EPICs to be distributed throughout the System Engineering team.
- Maintained Rancher Google Kubernetes Environment and updated certificates, updated Rancher Platform, redirected
  to log aggregator, and reviewing cluster and pods are functioning properly with the assistance of CheckMK and
  DataDog.

- Participated in a hackathon that automated debt buyers as a direct company revenue of \$270k \$390k.
- Received an All Tech Award 2020 for Integrity for participating in multiple daylight savings responsibilities.

#### Senior Site Reliability Engineer

### First Republic Bank, Aug 2018 – Jan 2019

- Proactively monitored, maintained, troubleshooted, repaired and upgraded servers, network infrastructure, software services, power distribution and environmental systems for internal network as well as monitoring of connectivity to vendors, partners and subsidiaries.
- Monitored microservices on AWS environment and collaborated with other departments and vendors on troubleshooting urgent, upgrade, and ongoing issues.
- Implemented PowerShell scripts that reduce manual tasks to compare the completion of virtual image template reports.
- Responded to Cisco Identity Service Engine alerts by troubleshooting unauthorized devices in the production and non-production network.
- Built Windows Servers and RedHat virtual instances through multiple clusters in ESXi.
- Coordinated with Information Security Network Engineers to assign proper VLAN and subnets for newly built virtual servers to be placed in proper security groups in both production and non-production environments.
- Identified and coordinated with other departments to resolve issues related to virtual and physical technical issues located in the primary, secondary, and disaster recovery data centers.
- Provided joint technical experiences to troubleshoot individual branch outages that are related to system or network high availability infrastructure.
- Maintained and managed Windows ADM accounts to allow administrators access to appropriate platforms.
- Developed, configured, monitored, troubleshooted and maintained complex enterprise-wide file transfers and coordinating with internal and external contacts.
- Participated in disaster recovery and business continuity tests by performing recovery procedures and troubleshooting issues that may be encountered.
- Monitored and managed automated tasks such as system backups and scheduled tasks via Rundeck or Control-M.

# Senior Information Services Advisor

### Halcyon Financial Technology, Apr 2016 - Aug 2018

- Architected, project managed, implemented, and maintained small-to-medium sized environments delivering IT solutions utilizing a hybrid or full cloud architecture.
- Automated virtual instances with VMware by creating workstation and server templates.
- Implemented self-healing rules on Windows workstations and servers with Solarwind Nable.
- Monitored and managed intrusion prevention system and intrusion detection system (IPS/IDS) using Cisco Meraki Advanced Security platform, Sumologic, and Splunk.
- Attended annual IT meetings with Managing Partners, Chief Financial Officers, and Chief Security Officers to discuss high level projects such as migrating to Azure Enterprise and security implementation (BCP, DR, Data Breach).
- Performed cyber security audits to meet company requirements, SEC regulations, and FINRA regulations.
- Discovered vulnerabilities and performed remediation using Nessus, vulnerability scans, and Cylance, penetration testing.
- Managed and revised business continuity procedures and disaster recovery documentations for business-critical systems at multiple financial firms.
- Performed and provided executive reports on annual Datto disaster recovery testing by project managing and implementing Datto SIRIS 3 backup.
- Troubleshooted network related incidents across LANs, WANs, MPLs, and VPNs.

# Director of IT & Operations

**FixSwift,** Dec 2013 - Apr 2016

 Doubled company revenue from 2014 to 2015 by initiating new product lines. Provided technical guidance, professional development, and career progression to 12 employees.

#### System Administrator, Department of Service Bureau Solutions

Cisco Systems Inc, Sept 2010 - Oct 2012

 Responsible for system reliability on 60+ department servers (Cisco UCS Server, Cisco MCS-7800, HP Proliant Server, HP Storageworks SAN).

# Information Technology Support Specialist

**Covexxan,** Jun 2005 - Aug 2008

 Assembled touch screen desktops and implemented modifications to internal layouts to accommodate hardware peripherals.